[](#privacy-policy-1)Privacy Policy
===================================

The following Privacy Policy applies exclusively to data collected through our website. It does not cover any information collected offline.

### [](#what-information-do-we-collectcollect-2)[What information do we collect?](#collect)

We collect the information that you provide when you register on our site and gather additional data whenever you participate in the forum by reading, writing, and evaluating the content shared here.

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name and email address. You may, however, visit our site without registering. Your email address will be verified by an email containing a unique link. If that link is visited, we know that you control the email address.

When registered and posting, we record the IP address that the post originated from. We also may retain server logs which include the IP address of every request to our server.

### [](#what-do-we-use-your-information-foruse-3)[What do we use your information for?](#use)

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

* To personalize your experience — your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.
* To improve our site — we continually strive to improve our site offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.
* To improve customer service — your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
* To send periodic emails — the email address you provide may be used to send you information, notifications that you request about changes to topics or in response to your user name, respond to inquiries, and other requests or questions.

### [](#how-do-we-protect-your-informationprotect-4)[How do we protect your information?](#protect)

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information.

### [](#what-is-your-data-retention-policydata-retention-5)[What is your data retention policy?](#data-retention)

We will make a good faith effort to:

* Retain server logs containing the IP address of all requests to this server no more than 90 days.
* Retain the IP addresses associated with registered users and their posts no more than five years.

### [](#do-we-use-cookiescookies-6)[Do we use cookies?](#cookies)

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow). These cookies enable the site to recognize your browser and, if you have a registered account, associate it with your registered account.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences for future visits and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

### [](#do-we-disclose-any-information-to-outside-partiesdisclose-7)[Do we disclose any information to outside parties?](#disclose)

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our site, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

### [](#what-about-third-party-linksthird-party-8)[What about third-party links?](#third-party)

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third-party products or services on our site. These third-party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

### [](#where-can-i-access-data-about-medata-access-9)[Where can I access data about me?](#data-access)

You can see your account data at any time by visiting your account page on the forum. Your account page also lists your posts and other activity on the forum.

Your account activity page also includes a link to download all of your activity in standard comma-separated values format.

### [](#how-can-i-change-or-erase-data-about-meerase-10)[How can I change or erase data about me?](#erase)

You can change your account data or completely close your account at any time by visiting the profile settings page for your account. Closing your account starts a process of erasing or anonymizing the forum’s records of data you provided for your account. Forum administrators can also erase and anonymize accounts.

Depending on the settings for your particular forum, you may also be able to edit, anonymize, or erase your posts. When you edit posts, the forum will keep all versions of your posts. Forum administrators can view old versions of posts, and optionally make them visible to other forum visitors.

### [](#do-we-comply-with-the-childrens-online-privacy-protection-actcoppa-11)[Do we comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act?](#coppa)

Our site, products, and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older. If this server is in the USA, and you are under the age of 13, per the requirements of COPPA ([Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act)), do not use this site.

### [](#do-i-have-to-agree-to-the-privacy-policyconsent-12)[Do I have to agree to the Privacy Policy?](#consent)

By using our site, you consent to our website Privacy Policy, as well as our [Terms of Service](https://forum.zcashcommunity.com/tos).

### [](#does-the-privacy-policy-ever-changechanges-13)[Does the Privacy Policy ever change?](#changes)

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page as well as in the [Meta category of the Zcash Forum](https://forum.zcashcommunity.com/c/meta).

_This document is made available under a [CC BY-SA license](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.0/). It was last updated September 26, 2018 (purely formatting changes)._

Powered by [Discourse](https://www.discourse.org/), best viewed with JavaScript enabled
